Ayesha A. Awan

Education Research Professional

ayeshawan@yahoo.com

Summary

Over ten years of experience designing and conducting policy relevant research and evaluation studies for key education issues in Pakistan. Areas of study have included student assessment systems, student achievement, data effectiveness, citizenship education, community participation, and early childhood education.

Experience

Research Advisor at Campaign for Quality Education (CQE)

January 2012 - Present (2 years 6 months)

- Advise on research and analysis for studies on assessment, teacher education, language of teaching, citizenship and other key issues.
- Conceptualize, develop, promote social studies education website, Humshehri, which seeks to enhance understanding of Pakistan's history, culture, places and people.

Consultant at The World Bank

November 2013 - March 2014 (5 months)

• Provided technical assistance and implementation support to key institutions in Punjab for strengthening examination and assessment systems.

Research Team Leader at DFID ILM Ideas Project, SAHE

July 2012 - June 2013 (1 year)

• Designed and conducted research for project using Khan Academy instructional videos in government classrooms that included student performance control/treatment group comparisons as well as satisfaction surveys.

Research Mentor at Pre-STEP/USAID

March 2012 - December 2012 (10 months)

• Advised faculty at University of Balochistan on designing, conducting and analyzing case-based research on assessment techniques in the new B.Ed. (Hons) program.

Research Consultant at The World Bank

August 2011 - December 2011 (5 months)

• Conducted research on student assessment systems in Pakistan as a part of national education review and international benchmarking studies (SABER).

Research Component Leader at DFID Monitoring Study on Punjab Examination Commission, SAHE January 2011 - December 2011 (1 year)

• Led key study components on exam conduct and data interpretation of primary and elementary school

exams in 18 districts of Punjab.

• Developed dissemination strategy and presented recommendations to government and donors.

Research Analyst & Associate Coordinator at Campaign for Quality Education (CQE) at Society for Advancement of Education

March 2005 - April 2011 (6 years 2 months)

- Conducted research on school quality, community participation, student achievement and effective data use and evaluation of cluster based training programs.
- Developed research based advocacy messages and dissemination strategy through publications, policy dialogues, website and media.
- Managed CQE activities including development of strategy, grant proposals and budgets.

Research Manager at Sindh Education Foundation

July 2003 - June 2004 (1 year)

- Designed and managed M&E component of early childhood program in Sindh & Balochistan which included developing student assessments, classroom observations, household and community tools.
- Collaborated on development of indicators for early years Child Development Record with Aga Khan University Human Development Program.

Research Officer at Society for Community Support for Primary Education in Balochistan November 2002 - July 2003 (9 months)

• Supervised implementation of early childhood program in 5 districts and developed field staff understanding of early childhood development through training workshops.

Publications

Improving Education through Large-Scale Testing? A study on primary and elementary level exams in Punjab

SAHE: Lahore 2011

Authors: Abbas Rashid, Ayesha A. Awan, Irfan Muzaffar, Salaeya Butt

School Management Committees in Pakistan: Mobilising Communities for Education?

LUMS Social Science & Policy Bulletin, 3 (2), 15-19 2011

Authors: Abbas Rashid, Ayesha A. Awan

Courses

M.Ed., International Education Policy

Harvard University Graduate School of Education

Intermediate Statistics \$030 Ethnography of Education \$540

Languages

Urdu

Skills & Expertise

Qualitative Research Research Design **Proposal Writing SPSS Literature Reviews Data Analysis Educational Research Program Evaluation Policy Analysis** Research **Policy Education Policy Grant Writing Civil Society Capacity Building Analysis Report Writing NGOs**

Education

Training

Harvard University Graduate School of Education

M.Ed., International Education Policy, 2001 - 2002

Georgetown University

BA, Pyschology, Cultural Anthropology, 1996 - 1999

Ayesha A. Awan

Education Research Professional

ayeshawan@yahoo.com



Contact Ayesha A. on LinkedIn